The next algorithm I would like to show you is called Hybrid A*.
次にお見せしたいアルゴリズムは Hybrid A* と呼ばれています
To introduce you to Hybrid A*,
Hybrid A* を説明するために
I would like to share your video that Sebastian recorded for another class.
別のクラス用にセバスチャンが作成したビデオをお見せしようと思います
Afterwards, I'm going to ask you the same question
そのあと A*について回答した
about Hybrid A* that you just answered about A*.
Hybrid A* に関する同じ質問を尋ねます
So let's talk about robot path planning or robot motion planning.
それではロボットパスプランニングまたはロボットモーションプランニングについて お話ししましょう
Where just a rich field in itself and I
それ自体が非常に奥が深い分野であるため
can't give you a complete survey of all the items involved.
関連する全ての項目の完全な調査結果を伝えることができません
But one of the key differences to the planning as
でも 前にもお話ししたように プランニングでカギとなる違いの 1 つは
we talked about before is that now the word is continuous.
連続です
So for example, we've read about A* in which we discretize the world.
たとえば 世界を離散化する A* について読みました
You might have a goal location,
ゴールの場所があったり
you might have obstacles and then A*,
障害があったりするかもしれません
a valid action sequence might look like this.
A* は有効なアクションの順序はこのような感じかもしれません
And even though this is a valid solution to the planning problem,
これはプランニング問題には有効なソリューションですが
a car can't really follow these discrete choices.
車はこれらの個々の選択にはついていけません
There's a number of very sharp turns over here
ここには とても繊細な曲がり角がいくつかあります
that are just irreconcilable with the motion of a car.
これは車の動きだけでは解決できません
So the fundamental problem here is A* is
ここでの基本的な問題は A* は
discrete whereas the robotic world is continuous.
離散で ロボット工学の世界では継続します
So the question arises,
よって 出てくる質問は
is there version of A* that can deal with the continuous nature
A* はその本質のままで
and give us probably executable paths?
可能性のある実行可能なパスを提供できるのかということです
This is a big big question in robot motion planning.
これはロボットモーションプランニングではとても大きな質問です
And let me just discuss it for this one example and show you
また この 1 つの例についてだけお話し
what we've done to solve this problem with a duff probing challenge.
無意味な証明に挑戦してこの問題を解決するために行ったことをお見せします
So the key to solving this with A* has to do with a state transition function.
A* でこれを解決するカギは 状態遷移関数を使って行わなければなりません
Suppose we are in a cell like this and you play a sequence
このようなセルにいるとします
of very small steps simulations using our continuous math from before,
個々の状態は前の数式を引き続き使用して
then a state over here might find
小さいステップのシミュレーションの順序をやってみます
itself right here in the corner of the next discrete state.
その後 ここの状態は それ自体は 次の離散状態の端のちょうどここになることがわかります
Instead of assigning this just to the grid cell,
グリッドセルでこれを想定する代わりに
an algorithm called Hybrid A* memorizes the exact X prime Y prime and theta
Hybrid A* というアルゴリズムは 正確な X の素数 Y の素数 θ の素数を暗記し
prime and associate it with
ここでグリッドセルに関連付けて
the grid cell over here the first time the grid cell is expanded.
はじめてここでグリッドセルが展開されます
Then when expanding from the cell,
その後 セルから展開するとき
it uses a specific starting point over here to figure out what the next cell might be.
ここで特定の出発点を使用して 次のセルがどこになるかを見つけます
Now, it might happen that the same cell we used to get in A* maybe from over
ここで A* で取得するために使用した同じセルは
here going into a different continuous polymerization of X, Y and theta,
X Y および θ の異なる連続するポリメリゼーションに入りますが
but because in A* we tend to expand
A* では長いパスを見る前に 一番短いパスで
cells along the shortest path before we look the longer paths,
セルを展開しようとしたので
we not just cut this off and never consider to stay over here again.
ここを削除しただけではなく ここにもう一度と考えることもありませんでした
Now, this leads to a lack of completeness which
完成するまでの欠陥につながるかもしれません
means there might be solutions to
これが捉えられなかったナビゲーション問題に対する
the navigation problem that this algorithm doesn't capture.
ソリューションがあるかもしれないが
But it does give us correctness.
それは正しさを与えてくれます
So as long as our motion equations are correct,
モーションの方程式が正しい限り
the resulting paths can be executed.
結果のパスは実行できます
Now, here's a caveat.
ここに補足事項があります
This is an approximation and it's only correct
これは概算で このモーションの方程式が
to the point that these motions equations are correct or not correct.
正しいかどうかという点だけが正しいです
But nevertheless, all paths that come out are nice,
そうはいっても すべてのパスはよくて
smooth, and curved paths.
スムーズで 曲がったパスです
And every time we expand the grid cell,
グリッドセルを展開するといつでも
we memorize explicitly the continuous values of X prime,
このグリッドセルで X の素数 Y の素数 θ の素数の連続値を
Y prime and theta with this grid cell.
明確に暗記します